nuigalway.ie 2018-11-19

# Privacy - NUI Galway

##  Privacy Statement for the NUI Galway Web site

**Privacy Statement for the NUI Galway Web site**

The National University of Ireland Galway (the “University”) fully respects your right to privacy and takes every appropriate measure to secure the privacy of any information shared with the University. NUI Galway is the Data Controller of your personal data unless otherwise stated. The University acknowledges that such processing of Personal Data and Special Categories of Personal Data must meet the requirements of applicable Irish and European data protection legislation. Data Protection is the safeguarding of the privacy rights of individuals in relation to the processing of Personal and Special Categories of Personal Data. The Act, the Irish Data Protection Bill 2018 and the General Data Protection Regulation 2016 confer rights on individuals as well as responsibilities on persons and organisations processing personal data. 

**Purpose of Processing:**

The University obtains, processes, collects, keeps, uses, discloses (where permissible by law), and retains Personal Data and Special Categories of Personal Data (both as defined in: <https://gdpr-info.eu/art-4-gdpr/>  ) regarding its staff, students, service users and other individuals who come in contact with or engage in business with the University. The purposes of processing Personal Data and Special Categories of  Personal Data include but are not limited to the purposes set out in University Policies and Procedures available on the University website, fulfilling the University’s functions and obligations under the Universities Act 1997 (See <http://www.irishstatutebook.ie/eli/1997/act/24/enacted/en/html> ), the provision of educational courses and support services, the organisation and administration of courses, undertaking of research activities, the recruitment and employment of staff, compliance with statutory obligations, reporting to Government bodies,  the provision of commercial activities, the management of financial affairs, advertising and promoting the University, publishing University and alumni publications, and undertaking fundraising. The University also processes personal information through CCTV systems that monitor and collect visual images for the purposes of research, security and the prevention and detection of crime.

**User Volunteered Information:**

The University does not collect any personal information on this Web site without your permission. All information volunteered within online forms is treated as confidential in accordance with applicable Irish data protection legislation and with the General Data Protection Regulation 2016. Personal information requested by online forms shall be used for the purpose set out on the online form.

**Automatically Obtained Information**

Cookies are small text files placed on your browsing device and more information about cookies and how to manage or disable them can be found here: [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

Cookies may be used to collect non-personal information about how visitors use our website.

If a cookie does not contain an expiration date it is referred to as a temporary session cookie. Temporary session cookies are stored in memory and never written to disk, when the brower closes the cookie is permanently lost from this point on. Temporary session cookies may be used in some areas to enable specific functionality.

If the cookie contains an expiration date, it is considered a persistent cookie. On the date specified in the expiration, the cookie will be removed from the disk. Persistent cookies may be used to remember your display preferences (e.g. preferred text size) the next time you visit. These cookies exist on your computer for 30 days after you have visited but they contain no private or sensitive data.

We use cookies as part of Google Analytics, a Web analytics service that enables us to track how visitors use our website. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, instructions can again be found here: [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

Some cookies present on our site are not related to the University such as those that may be present on pages with embedded content from Facebook, Twitter and Instagram for example. The University does not have any control or influence on the operation of these third party cookies. You should check the websites concerned for more information in relation to their cookie policies.

Some  _browser header information_  is automatically stored by the system to generate website usage statistics. IP addresses are read by the website to identify users located on the NUI Galway campus in order to offer them internal functionality. Any other technical information automatically obtained by the system is clearly visible when filling out online forms - e.g. the 'Browser and Operating System' information in the '  _Report an Email Problem_ ' form.

The National University of Ireland Galway does not use  _malware_ ,  _spyware_ , or  _adware_  in any form or fashion.

**Legal Basis:**

For the majority of the activities set out in this statement the Universities Act 1997 and the University Charter and Statutes gives the University legal authority to process your personal data where this is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the University as Data Controller. The University also has the authority to carry out the above activities if these are required to complete the performance of a contract with you.  If you use optional free services, the legal basis is your consent which you can opt into these and withdraw your consent to them.

**Security:**

NUI Galway uses every appropriate physical and technical security measure to prevent unauthorised access, alteration or destruction of data. These measures are reviewed regularly.

**Information Disclosure:**

The National University of Ireland, Galway will not disclose any personal information obtained from its Web site to any third party unless it is in accordance with University Policy and applicable law.

**Contact Information:**

Any queries regarding privacy and this Website can be directed to [info@nuigalway.ie](mailto:info@nuigalway.ie)

**Your rights:**

You have a right to access your personal information, to object to the processing of your personal information, to rectify, to erase, to restrict and to port your personal information. For further information please visit: 

(1)  <http://gdprandyou.ie/>

(2)  <https://www.dataprotection.ie/docs/Home/4.htm>

Any requests or objections should be made in writing to the University Data Protection Officer:

The Data Protection Officer,   
NUI Galway, Room A129,   
The Quadrangle,   
NUI Galway,   
University Road,   
Galway 

**Email:**[dataprotection@nuigalway.ie](mailto:dataprotection@nuigalway.ie)

**How to make a complaint:**

If you are unhappy with the way in which your personal data has been processed, you may in the first instance contact the University Data Protection Officer using the contact details above.

If you remain dissatisfied, then you have the right to apply directly to the Data Protection Commissioner for a decision. She can be contacted at: -

**Telephone**

| 

+353 57 8684800

+353 (0)761 104 800 

|   
---|---|---  
  
**Lo Call Number**

| 

1890 252 231

|   
  
**Fax**

| 

+353 57 868 4757

|   
  
**E-mail**

| 

|    
  
**Postal Address**

| 

Data Protection Commissioner   
Canal House  
Station Road  
Portarlington   
R32 AP23 Co. Laois

|
